http://www.leisurelakesbikes.com/privacy-policy/

Checkout
FREE Delivery over £25 (Excluding Bikes)
GDPR Policy
With the new General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) that comes into effect 25th May 2018, we want to ensure that you fully understand the information we hold about you and the reasons we hold it.
When we collect your data:
* When you create an account with us online or instore
* When you visit our website and use your account to place an order
*When you engage with us on social media
* When you join our VIP club
* When you make a complaint to us
* When you enter competitions or sign up for arranged rides & demo days
* When you review our products & services
* When you’ve given a third party permission to share the information they hold about you with us
* When you apply to pay via one of our Finance suppliers, Hitachi or V12 Finance
* When you visit our stores, you may be picked up on our CCTV which are used for security
What do we collect:
Leisure Lakes Bikes © will be what’s known as the ‘Controller’ of the personal data you provide to us. We only collect the following basic, personal data about you which does not include any special type of information:
* Your name
* Your address
* Your telephone number
* Your email address
* Your order history
* Information regarding how you got to our website if you came through a 3rd party
* Cookie information from your PC
* Your social media name if you chose to contact us via this platform
How & why do we use your information:
We are committed to protecting your privacy and only use the information we hold about in in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulations. We will not collect any personal data from you we do not need to provide and oversee this service to you. No 3rd parties have access to your personal data unless the law allows them to do so.
* Your information is used primarily to process your order. If your order is to be delivered to you, we will share your name and address details with our courier company.
* If you have chosen to pay for your order via finance, we will be given details of your application by our finance provider. These details will only be used to obtain payment from the finance company.
* Your details will be shared with the relevant authorities in any cases of fraud or theft.
* Your details will be used to contact you regarding surveys and feedback which help improve our service to you.
*Your information is used to provide you with marketing information about our content, products, and services. If you have consented to receive marketing material from us, you may opt out at a later date. You have a right at any time to stop us from contacting you for marketing purposes.
* Your details will be used to send you communication required by law, for example updates to our privacy policy or important warranty and recall information relating to the products we have sold you previously.
How we protect your information:
* Our website is secured by “https” technology
* We do not store any card details, these are all held and processed by our third party providers, Sage Pay & PayPal
* Customer accounts in store cannot be accessed by anyone who does not need to access them for the purpose of completing a transaction, processing a refund or informing you of a recall.
How long we keep your information:
We will never keep your information longer than necessary. Order details will be kept on file indefinitely unless you specifically ask us to remove them. This is to ensure we can contact you should a warranty or recall issues arise.
Your rights regarding your information:
Under the new GDPR, you are entitled to:
* access the personal details we hold about you. This will be completed with 30 days of your request and, in most cases, you will not be charged for this
* correct the data we hold about you where it is incorrect, incomplete or out of date
* request the cessation of specific direct marketing
* withdraw your consent to us holding your data at any time
* be notified of any data breaches that may occur. In the very unlikely event that this happens, you will be informed as soon as possible.
Should you wish to obtain a copy of the data we hold about you or if you wish to raise a complaint on how we have handled your personal data, you can contact our Data Protection Officer who will investigate the matter:
Data Protection Officer
Leisure Lakes Bikes
Wham Farm
155 Longmeanygate
Midge Hall
Preston
PR26 7TB
or alternatively email sar@leisurelakesbikes.com
If, for any reason, we are unable to action your request we will contact you with our reasons why.
Complaints
If for any reason you feel we have mis-handled your data or are unhappy with any of our responses to your requests, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO).
You can contact them by telephone on 0303 123 1113 or via their website: www.ico.org.uk/concerns
Our Website Cookies Policy
A cookie is a small file of text which we transfer to your hard drive through your web browser, as with most websites, when you visit our website and use certain pages or features on the site, especially when placing an order. It enables our own system to recognise you when you visit our website again and improve our service to you. This information can be used to enhance the content of our website and make your use of it easier. For more information about cookies please visit www.allaboutcookies.org
Cookies
When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally.
These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example:
- enabling a service to recognise your device so you don't have to give the same information several times during one task
- recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested
- measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast
You can manage these small files yourself and learn more about them through Internet browser cookies - what they are and how to manage them.
Our use of cookies
When we provide services, we want to make them easy, useful and reliable. Where services are delivered on the internet, this sometimes involves placing small amounts of information on your device, for example, your computer or mobile phone. These include small files known as cookies. They cannot be used to identify you personally.
These pieces of information are used to improve services for you through, for example:
- recognising that you may already have given a username and password so you don't need to do it for every web page requested
- measuring how many people are using services, so they can be made easier to use and there's enough capacity to ensure they are fast
- analysing anonymised data to help us understand how people interact with govt services so we can make them better
You can manage these small files and learn more about them from the article, Internet Browser cookies- what they are and how to manage them.
Learn how to remove cookies set on your device.
There are two types of cookie you may encounter when using Leisure Lakes Bikes :
First party cookies: these are our own cookies, controlled by us and used to provide information about usage of our site.
Third party cookies: these are cookies found in other companies' internet tools which we are using to enhance our site, for example Facebook or Twitter have their own cookies, which are controlled by them.
First party cookies
*Leisure Lakes Bikes uses cookies in several places - we've listed each of them below with more details about why we use them and how long they will last.
We will endeavour to let you know before we store a cookie on your computer.
Our Own PERSISTANT cookies
Name
Purpose
Typical content
_Session
This cookie speeds up your experience on our website if you visit us more than once by remembering key information if you have set your browser to allow it. For example your username when logging in, or your preferences when browsing our website.
It is an anonymous customer ID cookie, so we do not save any specific data about you at all, just a unique _Session reference number
Cookies set by Leisure Lakes Bikes website
Name
Purpose
Expires
ASP.NET_SessionId
HttpReferer
Referer
dd_object
These only last for the session (visit) to our website, and help with your movement through the website, and also let us know if you have visited from a 'Referer' i.e. another website where we may have a link, or an article about us.
Expires on exit
Third party cookies
We use a number of suppliers who may also set cookies on their websites' on its behalf. Leisure Lakes Bikes do not control the dissemination of these cookies. You should check the third party websites for more information about these.
Provider
Name
Purpose
More Info
Google Analytics
_utma
_utmb
_utmc
_utmz
These cookies are used to collect information about how visitors use our site. We use the information to compile reports and to help us improve the site. The cookies collect information in an anonymous form, including the number of visitors to the site, where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited. They do not contain any personally identifiable information.
Google Privacy policy
Add This
_atuvc
The _atuvc cookie is created and read by our JavaScript on the client side in order to make sure the user sees the updated count if they share a page and return to it before our share count cache is updated. No data from that cookie is sent back to AddThis.
Add This privacy
Changes to this privacy policy
If this privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.
You can use the settings of your browser to block, or delete cookies as you wish. Do please note that blocking cookies may slow down your experience on our website, or cause issues with placing an order, as cookies are often required to help with a smooth checkout process!
If you have any questions about our cookies policy or feedback please contact us on 01772 644340 or via our contact us page link at the top of the page.
Quick Links
FREE Click + Collect on everything!
Order online today and collect in any of our 11 UK stores for FREE!
Find your local LLB Store
FREE Delivery over £25 (Excluding Bikes)
We offer FREE UK Delivery on everything over £25 online (excluding bikes)! Want it in a hurry? Select the premium delivery option! We also deliver across Europe!UK EXTENDED AREA DELIVERYIf you’re in an extended area postcode, there may be a delay on our normal services and a surcharge for delivery. This will be calculated when entering your postcode at the checkout.• Zone 1: England, Wales & parts of Scotland excl. Highlands & Islands• Zone 2: Highlands & Islands of Scotland• Zone 3: Northern Ireland, Isle of Man & Isles of ScillyEvery bike we sell is built, tested and packed securely within 24 hours of placing your order - in one of our special Leisure Lakes Bikes boxes by a Cytech qualified mechanic.We do this PDI (pre-despatch inspection) to make sure everything is set up correctly and safely for you.
View Delivery Options
0% Finance on all orders over £275
Split your monthly payments with 0% finance on ALL orders over £275! Apply online for home delivery or in any of our 11 UK stores!
View Finance Options
Hassle Free Returns
Not happy with your purchase? Send it back to us or return in any of our stores and we will give you a full refund or exchange!
View Returns options
Live chat
FREE Delivery over £25 (Excluding Bikes)
Leisure Lakes Bikes ©
Credit subject to status and affordability. Terms & Conditions Apply.
trading as Leisure Lakes Bikes are a credit broker and are Authorised and Regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority. Credit is provided by Hitachi Personal Finance, a division of Hitachi Capital (UK) PLC Authorised and Regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority. Hitachi Capital (UK) PLC is authorised and regulated by the Financial Conduct Authority. Financial Services Register no. 704348. The register can be accessed through http://www.fca.org.uk
Subscribe
Ts&Cs
Privacy & Cookies
by Citrus-Lime
To improve your shopping experience today and in the future, this site uses cookies.
